Guide to the Records of the Administrative Services Office, New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, 1905-1978
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Records of the Administrative Services Office
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Administrative Services Office, New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences; 1905-1978, 1961-1978 (bulk)
21-2-2142
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Administrative Services.
3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notes, lists, reocrds.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records include correspondence and memoranda on facilities and projects, program notes, and equipment lists. Also building and construction records.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records include correspondence and memoranda on facilities and projects, program notes, and equipment lists. Also building and construction records.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Buildings.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- AG Quad - WKK File (Redvelopment Study), 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Old Road Maps (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Requests for Maps, Weather Information, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 2a)
- Capital Construction, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Construction - CALS, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Large animal research lab., facitlity program, equipment requirments, reduced floor plans of Morrison Hall, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Estimate of turkey cost of the beef cattle, sheep, and swine units (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agronomy - Plant Breeding - Conservation Building (Box 1, Folder 7)
  A. Facilities, furnishings, and equipment (groups 1, 2, 3)
  B. Program
  C. Grouping of rooms according to physcial association
  Correspondence, proposal
- Large Animal Research Facility - Animal Science Research Farm, dairy cattle unit, 1965-1967 proposal; specifications for relocation; equipment requirements (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Plant Breeding Filed House, program equipment requirements, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Poultry Facilities Proposal, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Budget and program report for renovation and rehabilitiation of Plant Science Building, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Space Needs (General), 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Large animal research unit (Experiemntal Animal Lab.), Dept. of Animal Husbandry, 1969 program, equipment requirements (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Greenhouse and growth chambers, phase I and II (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Livestock Pest Control Facility; program, equipment list, correspondence, line dwg. of rooms, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Calf Research Facility - proposal, prelim. plans, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Stocking Hall and Riley Robb, space use study, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- College Space Allocation, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Dondero Lab. rehab., Stocking Hall (O'Brien Lab), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Building Programs, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- College Projects, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Capital Improvements and Rehabilitation Projects, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Building Plans, Dept. of Poultry Science, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- New Food Science Building - space use study, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Space Survey, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Potter Lab., Stocking Hall, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Freeville Field Laboratory; Program; Equipment Requirements, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- "Raising and Finishing Holstein Steers for Beef," by Arthur C. Mengel of St. Lawrence University; Research proposal; Facitlity requirements for calf rearing, barn and steer feeding shed (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Preparation of Campus Academic Plan and Campus Development; Instructions governing processing; Plant pathology response, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Facility improvement projects, proposed; Seed potato farm, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Capitol projects for Colleges of Agriculture and Home Economics (questions from NYS Division of Budget), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Franzen Report on Architectural Evaluation of Existing Bldgs., 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- College Funded Projects Study, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- College Funded Renovation Requests/Projects, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Renovation Requests, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Renovation Requests, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Renovation Requests, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Renovation Requests, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Renovation Requests, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Capitol Budget Requests, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Capitol Construction, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Entomology - Plant Pathology Building Proposals, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Construction Costs, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Building Program - Ag. and Life Sciences (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Inclues: 1. List of Building Proposals, July 25, 1968
  2. Master Campus Plan: Facilties, NYS College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, a Statutory College of the State University, Cornell University - W.K. Kennedy, Dean, Oct. 22, 197? (Draft)
  3. Mission of the NYS College of Ag. and Life Sciences - A Stautory Coll. of the State University at Cornell Univ., Ithaca, NY, Sept. 10, 1974 (Draft)
- Building Space Programming (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Includes: 1. Tentative Building Sequence - Agriculture, Apr. 15, 1971
  2. Academic Space by Departments, Apr. 15, 1971
  3. Proposed Building Sequence, Apr. 15, 1971
  4. Organizational Structure (by function)
- Farm Census Materials, 1950-1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Lands Used and Livestock Kept - Report by NYS College of Agriculture - S. Rueben Shapley, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Campus Plan - Geneva, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Campus Plan for Facilities, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Comprehensive Campus Planning - Report beginning with Info. of 1868 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Campus Plan, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Includes: 1. Campus Plan for Facilities, Nov. 1, 1974
  Agriculture and Life Sciences Redevelopment Plan, Mar. 1, 1974
  3. Policies Adopted as a Guide to Development of Cornell Campus, Dec. 14, 1971
  4. Tentative Building Sequence, Agriculture, Apr. 15, 1971
  5. A Proposed Cooperative Education Program, NYS College of Agriculture, Cornell, Jan. 1971
  6. Enrollment Goals
- Ad Hoc Committee to Study 1972 Master Planning Symposia Papers (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Master Plan, College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Master Plan, Master Plan Appendices, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- CU Master Plan, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Progress Report on Implementation of the Master Plan, 1976, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Basic Guidelines for Campus Master Plan, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Long Range Campus Plan for SUNY and Ag. School, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Projected Full-Time Undergraduate Enrollments for NYS through 1990, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Report of the Committee on Master Planning for Higher Education in NYS (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Correspondence re Repairs in Agriculture School, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Cornell - Boyce Thompson Institute Affiliation Agreement, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Boyce Thompsom Institute, Misc. Information, 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Boyce Thompson Institute, Annual Reports, (#48, 49, 50, 53) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Fernow Hall, 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Geneva Buildings, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Includes: A. List of Buildings at NYS Ag. Experiment Station
  B. Program for Ag. Chemicals Bldg.
- Greenhouse Space nad Greenhouses (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Guteman, Correspondence, etc., 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Reports - "Facility Program for Greenhouse and Related Facilities," and "Guteman Bioclimatic Laboratories" (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Kenneth Post Lab, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Space - R.T. Clausen (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Miner Institute, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Report from Building Comm., "Space Requests for a New Animal Husbandry Bldg.", 1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Ornamentals Research Lab, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Plant Breeding Field House, H.H. Love, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Rice Hall, Reports - "Request for Renovation Funds," and "Life Safety Exit Requirements Report...", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Riley-Robb, Program Reports, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Schwardt, Large Animal Pest Control, 1967-1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- State Shops, Departmental Responsibilities (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Lease Renewal for 640 Stewart Ave., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Stocking 209 Renovation - Stocking 1, 2, 3, 10 Renovation, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Toxic Chemicals Lab, Information, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Valatie Farm, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- V-N Lab, Air Conditioning, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Veg. Research Farm, Freeville Field Lab, 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Includes: A. Freeville Field Laboratory, Report from 1970
- Warren Farm, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Greenbelt - Information, 1971 (Box 3)
  Includes: A. Report, "Greenbelt - Revised Agricultural Lands"
- Mt. Pleasant Timber Harvest (Box 3)
- Migrant Labor re Cohn Farm, 1971 (Box 3)
  Includes: A. Report, "The Migrant Labor Situation - A Proposed Strategy"
  B. Report, "Migrant Labor - Teaching, Research, and Policy"
- Ag. Engineering - Proposed Greenhouse Site - Riley Robb (Box 3)
- Agronomy, Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
- Animal Science, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 3)
- Plantations, Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 3)
- Food Science - Stocking Hall - and "Space Needs for Food Science" (Report), 1972 (Box 3)
- Ecology and Systematics - Reports and Letters, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  Includes: A. Propsal for Systematics Facility 1963
  B. Propsal for Systematics Facility 1964
- Report, "The L.H. Bailey Hortorium - An Assessment of the President; A Plan for the Future", 1972 (Box 3)
- Annual Reports, 1971-1975 (Box 3)
- East Ithaca - Low Income Housing, 1971 (Box 3)
- Route 13 Plans (Improvement of Route 13) (Box 3)
- Action Program - Construction, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
- Conference Center - Space Estimates, 1947 (Box 3)
- Incineration of Waste Products - Proposal, 1971 (Box 3)